Looks like Enthropic is finally back
with the launch of Claude Sonnet 4.5 and
it's truly remarkable as Enthropic has
stated it to be the best coding model in
the world. It's the strongest model for
building complex agents. It's the best
model at using computers and it shows
substantial gains on tests of reasoning
and math. But what's wild is the fact
that this new 4.5 Sonnet model is
outperforming even Opus 4.1 on the
Swaybench verified test, which is wild.
This is the most aligned Frontier model
that they've ever released, showing
large improvements across several areas
of alignment compared to the previous
Cloud models. The Sonic 4.5 has text and
image inputs and has a 200K context
window which isn't too large but with a
1 million context beta available. It
also has a max output of 64k tokens and
the training data cutoff of July 2025.
Now, in regards to its pricing, it's
still currently priced as the same
pricing structure as the Sonnet 4, where
it's listed at $3 for 1 million input
tokens and $15 per 1 million output
tokens. But its performance is just
truly remarkable. on the Swaybench
verify test. It was able to maintain
focus for over 30 hours which they have
stated on complex multi-step tasks and
it was able to lead on various sorts of
benchmarks against many of these
proprietary models like GBT 5 codecs,
GBT 5 itself as well as Gemini 2.5 Pro.
But I feel like these guys are going to
definitely overtake all of these models
next week. But overall, the Sonnet 4.5
is still relatively amazing. And in
terms of its performance, it does really
well across every sort of coding
benchmark. It also leads on the OS world
computer use benchmark with a score of
61.4 percentage and it's a huge jump
from Sonnet 4 which recorded a 42.2. But
in regards to other Agentic terminal
tasks as well as regular Aentic tasks,
it does a great job and it outperforms
many of these other models across all of
these different tasks, which is just
quite impressive. And surprisingly, this
model does really well with reasoning
and math and it advances make Sonnet 4.5
as one of the most powerful and capable
of reasoning models, but in terms of its
coding performance and a Gentic use, it
is definitely the best that's out there.
There's also a Claude agent SDK and
there is also a new bonus research
preview where essentially they have
named this product Imagine with Claude
and it's a new way for you to actually
build any sort of app and use their
Sonnet 4.5 to help build anything and I
believe this is only available to the
paid Enthropic plans. Now, if you're
looking to get started, you can
definitely do so with the cloud API. You
can also use it through their chatbot
completely for free, but I believe it is
rate limited heavily. Now, if you're
looking to access this via API for free,
you can use Kilo code cuz I believe they
offer $25 worth of free credits, which
is remarkable. So, definitely recommend
that you try this out. And lastly, you
also have Open Router where you can use
it. But now, let's actually start
testing this out. First off, we're going
to have it build a browserbased OS.
Essentially, this is a prompt that is
going to test the model's ability for
its code generation, obviously, as well
as its system design. We were trying to
see how well it is in terms of planning
and writing a complex front end and even
working on having it so that it creates
all the components for a web- based
operating system. We're trying to see
how well it is in terms of using
reasoning as well as tool and resource
use. So, it looks like it's doing pretty
good. It's the same speed, I believe, as
the Sonnet. Uh, you can't really test it
off of the chatbot, but we'll get a
better idea of it when we're in a coding
agent like Hilo Code,
but looks like it has finished
developing this. And in a single shot,
it looks like it has finished generating
our browser OS, which actually looks
pretty nice. Let's go now to the link to
visualize it. And we can actually see
that there's three different apps at
Code Route. There is a file manager.
There's also a terminal that it has
actually developed as well as a
calculator that actually works. Now, all
of this was fully developed in a single
shot with the browser chatbot. Imagine
if we were to send it to an agent. We
would get such a great generation out of
it. Now, I told it to add more features
and it looks like it has done that by
adding a couple of different
applications like a notepad, which is
cool. There's also settings and it is
also adding a couple other things like a
painter. It looks like it did a great
job in generating the base structure for
this browserbased OS and it did a pretty
quick job at it. Before we get started,
I just want to mention that you should
definitely go ahead and subscribe to the
World of AI newsletter. I'm constantly
posting different newsletters on a
weekly basis. So, this is where you can
easily get up-to-date knowledge about
what is happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. Now heading
into kilo code which is the autonomous
AI agent I primarily use. Now I can now
go over to the model provider and search
up 4.5 sonnet and we can actually select
this using the free API and we can send
in any prompt like create a SAS landing
page that has many features as well as
animations. We're trying to see how well
it is in terms of its front-end
designing, its creativity, as well as
its UX awareness where it can suggest
visual elements as well as flow
improvements. So, right away you can see
that it has thinking enabled and it is
now working on generating the SAS
landing page for us. So, looks like it
has finished generating the code. It
took approximately $2 to generate this
AI SAS landing page. And you can see it
looks pretty good. In terms of adding
animations, it did do that and the
structure looks pretty detailed and
overall it doesn't actually look like a
typical AI generated website in my
opinion. Now, overall got the main
structure right of a typical SAS landing
page with testimonials, a pricing
structure as well as an FAQ that has
animations. The bottom footer looks
perfect and it did a decent job with the
front end in my opinion. It's not the
best. It's not something extraordinary,
but still a decent SAS landing page. I
asked the chatbot, and this is the
generation I've gotten for the SAS
landing page. And in this case, I haded
to tell it to make it better after the
first prompt that sent in. And it does
look decent, but at the same time, it's
not like something that is super
impressive in terms of this testing of a
SAS landing page. Next up, we're going
to have the model work on creating a
butterfly in SVG code. and we're trying
to see how well the model is in
outputting proficient SVG code as well
as if it's able to develop this symmetry
of a butterfly in terms of its
structure. Let's head over to an online
SVG viewer. And now we can paste in the
SVG code. And there we go. We actually
have a pretty decent looking butterfly.
And it looks like the main structure
looks great. The symmetry is there. The
only thing that I would have a concern
with is the wings not being on top of
the body. And it looks like a butterfly
from far away, but then again, there's
certain components like this dot over
here that shouldn't be there. I don't
know. It's just what I would not expect
on a butterfly. Next up, I'm going to
have it create a Minecraft clone, which
is a really good prompt to test the
model's ability to handle large scale
code processes. And essentially we're
trying to see how well it is in terms of
developing the game architecture, how
well it is in terms of designing the
core systems of like the terrain could
be the generation and and essentially
we're trying to see if it's able to be
persistent with the multi-step task of
generating this game. So it looks like
it has finished testing and playing
around with what it has generated in
terms of its Minecraft clone. Let's now
open this up and let's see how well it
did in terms of generating it. Now, if I
click on this, I'll be then pasted into
this game. And you can see that it
actually did a pretty decent job in
replicating everything apart of
Minecraft in terms of the grass blocks.
Didn't generate much of the other
terrain, but you can see that I have the
ability to actually break blocks. And I
can actually go down and move around.
And if I wanted to, I can even place
down different blocks, which is pretty
cool. And in my opinion, it did a great
job in generating the base structure, I
guess, of the terrain. It'd be great if
I can iterate on it further and generate
other things like the trees as well as
other terrains. But overall, it did a
great job with this code, and I would
give it a pass aside from the trees.
Here is a demo of the Cloud Sonet 4.5
delivering one of the best or most
impressive oneshot solar system
implementations. It was able to generate
a fully functional planetary system with
realistic orbits. The physics looks
great and in terms of its interactions,
it was able to fully develop all of
these different components in a single
prompt. If you like this video and would
love to support the channel, you can
consider donating to my channel through
the super thanks option below. Or you
can consider joining our private Discord
where you can access multiple
subscriptions to different AI tools for
free on a monthly basis plus daily AI
news and exclusive content plus a lot
more. What I noticed though is its agent
capabilities as well as its front-end
capabilities have been improved
drastically. is able to do a lot better
in that front. But in certain other
cases, it feels like it's a bit short
with its code generation. Maybe it's its
context window, or maybe it's cuz the
quality of certain areas is not refined
yet, which we could see improvements
with the Cloud 5 release maybe in the
next couple of months. But that's
essentially it for today's video on
Claude Sonic 4.5. Let me know what you
guys think about this model. I'll leave
all these links in the description
below. It's definitely an impressive
model, but let's see what you guys
think. I'm definitely keen to hear what
you guys are wondering about these
different generations. But with that
thought, guys, thank you guys so much
for watching. Have an amazing day.
Subscribe to the second channel if you
haven't already. Make sure you go ahead
and join the newsletter, join the
private Discord, follow me on Twitter,
and lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos cuz there's a lot
of content that you'll definitely
benefit from. But with that thought,
guys, have an amazing day. Spread
positivity, and I'll see you guys really
shortly. He suffers.